<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PSF Outreach &amp; Education</title><link href="http://psf-outreach.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://psf-outreach.org/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://psf-outreach.org/</id><updated>2012-10-05T11:30:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Kenneth Gonsalves Posthumously Awarded Community Service Award</title><link href="http://psf-outreach.org/2012/10/05/kenneth-gonsalves-posthumously-awarded.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-05T11:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Brian Curtin</name></author><id>tag:psf-outreach.org,2012-10-05:2012/10/05/kenneth-gonsalves-posthumously-awarded.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Python Software Foundation, represented by director David Mertz, posthumously awarded Kenneth &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ilugcbe.org.in/index.php?title=Kenneth_Gonsalves"&gt;Gonsalves&lt;/a&gt; with the foundation’s Community Service &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.python.org/community/awards/psf-awards/"&gt;Award&lt;/a&gt; for the third quarter. The award was presented to his daughter last weekend at PyCon &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://in.pycon.org/2012/"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth passed away on August 3, 2012 at the age of 59. After finding the open source world in 1995, he was drawn to the Python community in 2003 and has since taught over 50 seminars on Python and Django in his area. He was also a major contributor to many mailing lists, generously helping as many people as he could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth was known for founding and leading the Indian Python Software &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/ipss"&gt;Society&lt;/a&gt;, and is credited with helping to shape the Python community all across India. He was also a well known member of the Django community, where his presence and action will surely be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of software, Kenneth took interest in golf, even becoming a referee and earning international certification. Throughout his time as an official he was assigned to several national tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Community Service Award, the foundation presented a grant of $3500 USD (~190K Rs) to the IPSS to seed an award in Kenneth’s name. The award is planned to be given annually to a community member who goes above and beyond to evangelize, innovate, and mentor other members of the Python community. As much of Kenneth’s work was focused on students, the IPSS wants to see further efforts in growing their community and educating the membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="images/KennethGonsalves.jpg" src="images/KennethGonsalves.jpg" /&gt;
</summary><category term="Community Service Awards"></category></entry><entry><title>Talk and Tutorial Proposals Due Today!</title><link href="http://psf-outreach.org/2012/09/28/pycon-proposals-due.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-28T08:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Jesse Noller</name></author><id>tag:psf-outreach.org,2012-09-28:2012/09/28/pycon-proposals-due.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As my college self would have said: there’s no better time to start a project than the day it’s due. That day is today, and what’s due is a talk or tutorial proposal for PyCon 2013. Proposals will be accepted as long as it’s still the 28th somewhere in the world, so keep an eye on the clock!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talks are 30 or 45 minute sessions on whatever it is that you want to share. They run Friday March 15 through Sunday March 17 in Santa Clara, CA. From the web to the desktop or up in the clouds, Python is everywhere and we want to know what you’re doing with it. Each year it seems like the schedule gets better and better, so help us keep the streak alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tutorials are 3 hour courses held on the two days preceding the conference talks: March 13 and 14. Whether you’re a full-time educator or just have a topic that you know and want to teach, submit your tutorials today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See our Call for Proposals for the full details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and registration is open, so sign up! Early bird rates apply to the first 1000 tickets, so get ‘em while they’re hot. We’ve also opened financial aid applications, so please apply if you could use some help with your trip.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="PyCon"></category></entry><entry><title>Announcing the 2012 Distinguished Service Award - John Hunter</title><link href="http://psf-outreach.org/2012/09/14/distinguished-service-award-john-hunter.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-14T10:24:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Brian Curtin</name></author><id>tag:psf-outreach.org,2012-09-14:2012/09/14/distinguished-service-award-john-hunter.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Distinguished Service Award&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python Software Foundation voted unanimously on September 12, 2012 to authorize the creation of a new award: the Distinguished Service &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.python.org/community/awards/psf-distinguished-awards/"&gt;Award&lt;/a&gt;. The award is offered in recognition of long-term excellence in the Python community, and is intended to stand as the Foundation's highest honor. Whether for contributions of code, activism, evangelism, or for other services to Python and its global community, the Foundation seeks to honor those who have a record of sustained and prolific giving to the Python world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The award will not be made to a schedule, but as deserving candidates emerge. It comes with a check for $5,000, in simple recognition of the kind of devoted service for which the award will be presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full details of the award, and a list of recipients, can be found on the Foundation's awards &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.python.org/community/awards/psf-distinguished-awards/"&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Recipient&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inaugural recipient of the Distinguished Service Award is John Hunter, who passed away on August 28, 2012 after losing an all-too-brief battle with colon cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is survived by his wife Miriam and three daughters Clara, Ava, and Rahel. To mark his passing, the NumFOCUS Foundation has setup a memorial fund for the care and education of his three daughters at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://numfocus.org/johnhunter/"&gt;http://numfocus.org/johnhunter/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Hunter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are few projects in the Python world which have enjoyed the reach, longevity, and value that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://matplotlib.org/"&gt;matplotlib&lt;/a&gt; has offered in the 10 years since its creation. John Hunter, at the time a post-doctoral neurobiologist at the University of Chicago, started the matplotlib library as a way to work around downtime created by limited licensing for expensive proprietary tools. His choice to use Python was a bold one at the time, given Python's relatively young age, especially within the sciences. However, his efforts paid off and he was able to create an open alternative to allow him to continue analyzing epileptic seizure data in children without the limitations he was experiencing with other products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, John left the academic world and entered Chicago's finance industry, taking employment at TradeLink Securities. While there, he took his science background and matplotlib project into the field of quantitative analysis. In the ten years since matplotlib's creation, John brought three daughters into the world and cared for his family all while maintaining the number one spot on the matplotlib committer list. He became further involved in the numeric and scientific communities, presenting at conferences and expanding his involvement to the recently formed NumFOCUS Foundation, at which he was a founding board member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John's creation and contribution of matplotlib to not just the Python community, but to the science and mathematics communities, is truly an effort that will live on and continue to influence these communities and more for many years to come. Whether you found Python through matplotlib or matplotlib through Python, John Hunter's efforts have left a lasting mark on so many people in so many places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Distinguished Service Award, the Foundation will be contributing $3500 to a project which is currently in the works, the John Hunter Technical Fellowship. More details on this will follow.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="award"></category><category term="distinctive service award"></category><category term="matplotlib"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World!</title><link href="http://psf-outreach.org/2012/09/08/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lynn Root</name></author><id>tag:psf-outreach.org,2012-09-08:2012/09/08/hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello World!  Welcome to the Python Software Foundation's Outreach &amp;amp; Education blog!  Stay tuned for posts on are thoughts and doings.  Until then, may the zen of Python be with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>