<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>PSF Outreach &amp; Education</title><link>http://psf-outreach.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://psf-outreach.org/feeds/all.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 11:30:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><item><title>Kenneth Gonsalves Posthumously Awarded Community Service Award</title><link>http://psf-outreach.org/2012/10/05/kenneth-gonsalves-posthumously-awarded.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Python Software Foundation, represented by director David Mertz, posthumously awarded Kenneth &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ilugcbe.org.in/index.php?title=Kenneth_Gonsalves"&gt;Gonsalves&lt;/a&gt; with the foundation’s Community Service &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.python.org/community/awards/psf-awards/"&gt;Award&lt;/a&gt; for the third quarter. The award was presented to his daughter last weekend at PyCon &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://in.pycon.org/2012/"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth passed away on August 3, 2012 at the age of 59. After finding the open source world in 1995, he was drawn to the Python community in 2003 and has since taught over 50 seminars on Python and Django in his area. He was also a major contributor to many mailing lists, generously helping as many people as he could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth was known for founding and leading the Indian Python Software &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/ipss"&gt;Society&lt;/a&gt;, and is credited with helping to shape the Python community all across India. He was also a well known member of the Django community, where his presence and action will surely be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of software, Kenneth took interest in golf, even becoming a referee and earning international certification. Throughout his time as an official he was assigned to several national tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Community Service Award, the foundation presented a grant of $3500 USD (~190K Rs) to the IPSS to seed an award in Kenneth’s name. The award is planned to be given annually to a community member who goes above and beyond to evangelize, innovate, and mentor other members of the Python community. As much of Kenneth’s work was focused on students, the IPSS wants to see further efforts in growing their community and educating the membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="images/KennethGonsalves.jpg" src="images/KennethGonsalves.jpg" /&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Brian Curtin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:psf-outreach.org,2012-10-05:2012/10/05/kenneth-gonsalves-posthumously-awarded.html</guid><category>Community Service Awards</category></item><item><title>Talk and Tutorial Proposals Due Today!</title><link>http://psf-outreach.org/2012/09/28/pycon-proposals-due.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As my college self would have said: there’s no better time to start a project than the day it’s due. That day is today, and what’s due is a talk or tutorial proposal for PyCon 2013. Proposals will be accepted as long as it’s still the 28th somewhere in the world, so keep an eye on the clock!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talks are 30 or 45 minute sessions on whatever it is that you want to share. They run Friday March 15 through Sunday March 17 in Santa Clara, CA. From the web to the desktop or up in the clouds, Python is everywhere and we want to know what you’re doing with it. Each year it seems like the schedule gets better and better, so help us keep the streak alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tutorials are 3 hour courses held on the two days preceding the conference talks: March 13 and 14. Whether you’re a full-time educator or just have a topic that you know and want to teach, submit your tutorials today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See our Call for Proposals for the full details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and registration is open, so sign up! Early bird rates apply to the first 1000 tickets, so get ‘em while they’re hot. We’ve also opened financial aid applications, so please apply if you could use some help with your trip.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jesse Noller</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:psf-outreach.org,2012-09-28:2012/09/28/pycon-proposals-due.html</guid><category>PyCon</category></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>http://psf-outreach.org/2012/09/08/hello-world.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hello World!  Welcome to the Python Software Foundation's Outreach &amp;amp; Education blog!  Stay tuned for posts on are thoughts and doings.  Until then, may the zen of Python be with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">@econchick</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:psf-outreach.org,2012-09-08:2012/09/08/hello-world.html</guid></item></channel></rss>