<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>PSF Outreach &amp; Education</title><link>http://psf-outreach.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://psf-outreach.org/feeds/content.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><item><title>Talk and Tutorial Proposals Due Today!</title><link>http://psf-outreach.org/2012/09/28/talk-and-tutorial-proposals-due-today/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As my college self would have said: there’s no better time to start a project than the day it’s due. That day is today, and what’s due is a talk or tutorial proposal for PyCon 2013. Proposals will be accepted as long as it’s still the 28th somewhere in the world, so keep an eye on the clock!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talks are 30 or 45 minute sessions on whatever it is that you want to share. They run Friday March 15 through Sunday March 17 in
Santa Clara, CA. From the web to the desktop or up in the clouds, Python is everywhere and we want to know what you’re doing with it. Each year it seems like the schedule gets better and better, so help us keep the streak alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tutorials are 3 hour courses held on the two days preceding the conference talks: March 13 and 14. Whether you’re a full-time educator or just have a topic that you know and want to teach, submit your tutorials today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See our Call for Proposals for the full details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and registration is open, so sign up! Early bird rates apply to the first 1000 tickets, so get ‘em while they’re hot. We’ve also opened financial aid applications, so please apply if you could use some help with your trip.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jesse Noller</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:psf-outreach.org,2012-09-28:2012/09/28/talk-and-tutorial-proposals-due-today/</guid><category>PyCon</category></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>http://psf-outreach.org/2012/09/08/hello-world/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hello World!  Welcome to the Python Software Foundation's Outreach &amp;amp; Education blog!  Stay tuned for posts on are thoughts and doings.  Until then, may the zen of Python be with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">@econchick</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:psf-outreach.org,2012-09-08:2012/09/08/hello-world/</guid></item></channel></rss>